DENIS COHEN 1 of 3

CONTACT Information University of Mannheim Mannheim Centre for European Social Research (MZES)

68159 Mannheim

denis.cohen@mzes.uni-mannheim.de

+49 621 181 2876

denis-cohen.github.io

RESEARCH Interests

My research focuses on comparative voting behavior, political preferences and attitudes, and political competition in consolidated multiparty democracies. My methodological interests include hierarchical and measurement models, data visualization, strategies for causal identification, and Bayesian statistics.

CURRENT POSITION

Mannheim Centre for European Social Research (MZES), Mannheim, Germany

Postdoctoral Fellow, Data and Methods Unit

09/2018 -

EDUCATION

Humboldt University of Berlin, Berlin, Germany

Ph.D. in Political Science, Berlin Graduate School of Social 10/2014 - 08/2018 Sciences (BGSS).

- Thesis Title: When Supply Meets Demand: Context-Dependent Mechanisms of Radical Right Voting.
- Committee: Prof. Dr. Heike Klüver (supervisor), Prof. Ellen M. Immergut, PhD (co-supervisor), and Prof. Daniel Stegmüller, PhD (external committee member, Duke University)
- Grade: summa cum laude

Princeton University, Princeton, NJ, United States

Visiting Graduate Student, Princeton-Humboldt Exchange, 09/2015 - 05/2016 Department of Politics. Faculty Sponsor: Prof. Kosuke Imai.

University of Essex, Colchester, Essex, United Kingdom

M.Sc. Political Economy

10/2013 - 09/2014

- Thesis Title: Reproachful or Indifferent? Changes in Incumbent Party Support after the 2007 German Pension Reform.
- Supervisor: Daniel Stegmüller, PhD

Humboldt University of Berlin, Berlin, Germany

M.A. Social Sciences (temporarily enrolled)

04/2013 - 09/2013

B.A. Social Sciences

10/2009 - 03/2013

- Thesis Title: Radical Right Party Voting in Western Europe. Examining interactions between individual-level and party-level characteristics.
- Supervisors: Prof. Ellen M. Immergut, PhD and Konstantin Vössing, PhD

University of California at Berkeley, Berkeley, CA, United States

Undergraduate exchange student, Charles and Louise Travers 08/2011 - 05/2012 Department of Political Science.

Past Positions

Humboldt University of Berlin, Berlin, Germany

Research Associate, Chair for the Comparative Analysis of 10/2017 - 08/2018 Political Systems, Department of Social Sciences

Denis Cohen 2 of 3

RESEARCH ASSISTANCE	DFG project 'The Impact of Electoral Vulnerability on Policy Recalibration' at the Chair for the Comparative Analysis of Political Systems. Department of Social Sciences, HU Berlin	04/2013 - 08/2013
	Chair for the Comparative Analysis of Political Systems. Department of Social Sciences, HU Berlin	10/2012 - 03/2013
TEACHING ASSISTANCE	Applied Data Analysis by Prof. Mark A. Kayser, PhD Hertie School of Governance, Berlin	09/2016 - 12/2016
	Hierarchical Models by Prof. Jeff Gill, PhD Essex Summer School in Social Science Data Analysis	08/2015, 08/2016
	$Stata~\mathcal{C}~Math~Bootcamp~Programme$ by Dr. Alejandro Quiroz Flores Department of Government, University of Essex	10/2014
	Statistics $I+II$ by Prof. Dr. Martin Groß Research and Teaching Unit for Empirical Social Research. Department of Social Sciences, Humboldt University of Berlin	10/2010 - 07/2011
TEACHING	Explaining Political Preferences – Theory, Empirics & Applications. Undergraduate specialization module (4 hrs/week), HU Berlin.	04/2018 - 09/2018
	Explaining Electoral Support for Far Right Parties. Undergraduate seminar (2 hrs/week), HU Berlin.	10/2017 - 03/2018
	Grundkurs Vergleichende Politikwissenschaft und Internationale Beziehungen (Introduction to Comparative Politics and International Relations). Undergraduate seminar (2 hrs/week), HU Berlin.	10/2017 - 03/2018
GRANTS AND FELLOWSHIPS	Doctoral fellowship, Berlin Graduate School of Social Sciences	10/2014 - 09/2017
	Travel grant, ECPR General Conference 2017 in Oslo, German Academic Exchange Service (DAAD)	09/2017
	Research grant, EUROFORT Princeton-Humboldt Strategic Research Partnership, Cluster 2 (Immigration)	10/2015 - 01/2016
	Travel grant, Princeton Annual Workshop on European Integration, EUROFORT Princeton-Humboldt Strategic Research Partnership	05/2015
	Student fellowship, Heinrich Böll Foundation	10/2010 - 09/2014
	Student fellowship, German National Academic Foundation	10/2010 - 09/2014
Conference Presentations	EPSA Annual Conference, Vienna, Austria. ^{p,d}	06/2018
	Graduate Network Conference, Berlin, Germany. ^{p,d}	03/2018
	ECPR General Conference, Oslo, Norway. ^{p,d,c}	09/2017
	EPSA Annual Conference, Milan, Italy. p,d,c	06/2017
	EPSA Annual Conference, Brussels, Belgium. ^{p,d,c}	06/2016
	MPSA Annual Conference, Chicago, IL, United States. ^{p,d}	04/2016
	Graduate Network Conference, Florence, Italy. ^{p,d}	03/2015
	ECPR Graduate Student Conference, Innsbruck, Austria. ^p Presenter, ^d Discussant, ^c Panel Chair	07/2014

Denis Cohen 3 of 3

Additional Training	Causal Identification by James Lo, PhD. Essex Summer School in Social Science Data Analysis. Colchester, Essex, United Kingdom.	08/2016	
	Pooled Time-Series Cross-Sectional Analysis by Robert W. Walker, PhD. Essex Summer School in Social Science Data Analysis. Colchester, Essex, United Kingdom.	08/2015	
	Qualitative Comparative Analysis by Markus Siewert and Jonas Buche. BGSS, Berlin, Germany.	04/2015	
	Structural Equations and Causal Models by Prof. Dr. Peter Schmidt. Essex Summer School in Social Science Data Analysis. Colchester, Essex, United Kingdom.	08/2014	
	Modeling Heterogeneity by Daniel Stegmüller, PhD. Essex Summer School in Social Science Data Analysis. Colchester, Essex, United Kingdom.	08/2014	
	Advanced Methods Workshop <i>Inequality and Politcs</i> by Philipp Rehm, PhD. BGSS, Berlin, Germany.	07/2014	
	Multilevel Modeling by Andrew Fullerton, PhD. WZB Berlin, Germany.	12/2012	
SKILLS	Languages: German (native), English (fluent), French (moderate), Spanish (moderate)		
	Software: R, Stan, BUGS/JAGS, Stata, MPlus, Office, LATEX		